<CRDoc>[Congressional Record Volume <volume>160</volume>, Number <number>37</number> (<weekday>Wednesday</weekday>, <month>March</month> <day>5</day>, <year>2014</year>)]
[<chamber>Extensions</chamber> of Remarks]
[Page <pages>E305</pages>]
<congress>113</congress>
<session>2</session>
              <document_title>TRIBUTE TO LIEUTENANT COLONEL JOHN RAFFERTY</document_title>
                          <title>HON. JOHN R. CARTER</title>
                                <title>of texas</title>
                    <title>in the house of representatives</title>
                        <title>Wednesday, March 5, 2014</title>
  <speaker name="Mr. CARTER">Mr. CARTER</speaker>. <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">Mr. Speaker, I rise to pay tribute to Lieutenant Colonel 
John Rafferty of the United States Army for his extraordinary 
dedication to duty and service to our nation at the Deputy of the Army 
House Liaison Division on Capitol Hill. Lieutenant Colonel Rafferty 
will soon transition to the Legislative Director for the Commander of 
the International Security Assistance Force in Kabul, Afghanistan.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">Army Congressional Liaison officers provide an invaluable service to 
both the military and Congress. They assist Members and staff in 
understanding the Army's policies, actions, operations, and 
requirements. Their firsthand knowledge of military needs, culture, and 
tradition is a tremendous benefit to Congressional offices.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">A native of Great Falls, Virginia, Lieutenant Colonel Rafferty 
enlisted in the Army in 1987 and served in Germany with the 8th 
Infantry Division. Two years later, he left the active Army to return 
to college and pursue a commission as an Army Officer. He received his 
commission as Second Lieutenant in the Regular Army as a Field 
Artillery officer. During the next twenty years, LTC Rafferty served in 
a variety of tactical assignments, including service in 1st and 3rd 
Battalions of the 75th Ranger Regiment, staff officer in the 25th 
Infantry Division, command of two artillery batteries in the 1st 
Armored Division, and command of 1st Battalion, 319th Airborne Field 
Artillery Regiment of the 82nd Airborne Division. Along with becoming 
an Army Ranger and Master Parachutist, he served multiple combat tours 
in Iraq and Afghanistan. Additionally, he was selected as an exchange 
officer for the U.S. Marine Corps Amphibious Warfare School and for the 
United Kingdom Joint Services Command and Staff College with the 
British Military.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">Lieutenant Colonel Rafferty is both warrior and scholar. He holds a 
Bachelor of Arts Degree in History from Longwood College, a Master of 
Arts in Defense Policy from King's College-London, and a Master of 
Strategic Studies from the U.S. Army War College.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">His devotion to his country is matched only by his commitment to 
family. Lieutenant Colonel Rafferty is married to the lovely Tracey 
Lowery Rafferty. They're proud parents of a thirteen-year-old daughter, 
Erin, and a twelve-year-old son, Evan.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">Lieutenant Colonel Rafferty's great work has not gone unnoticed. His 
military awards include the Combat Action Badge, Expert Infantry Badge, 
three Bronze Star Medals, and the Iraq and Afghanistan Campaign Medals. 
He was inducted into the Honorable Order of Saint Barbara and is a 
Distinguished Member of both the 319th Airborne Field Artillery 
Regiment and 505th Parachute Infantry Regiment.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mr. CARTER">Mr. Speaker, it is my honor to recognize the selfless service of 
Lieutenant Colonel John Rafferty as he proceeds into the next chapter 
of his remarkable career and continues to serve the United States of 
America. I wish him the best as he continues to serve our great Nation 
and proceeds to the next chapter in his remarkable career.</speaking>
</CRDoc>