<CRDoc>[Congressional Record Volume <volume>160</volume>, Number <number>37</number> (<weekday>Wednesday</weekday>, <month>March</month> <day>5</day>, <year>2014</year>)]
[<chamber>Extensions</chamber> of Remarks]
[Pages <pages>E305-E306</pages>]
<congress>113</congress>
<session>2</session>
                     <document_title>RECOGNIZING DAN ``OX'' OCHSNER</document_title>
                         <title>HON. MICHELE BACHMANN</title>
                              <title>of minnesota</title>
                    <title>in the house of representatives</title>
                        <title>Wednesday, March 5, 2014</title>
  <speaker name="Mrs. BACHMANN">Mrs. BACHMANN</speaker>. <speaking name="Mrs. BACHMANN">Mr. Speaker, I rise today to honor Dan ``Ox'' Ochsner 
for more than a 
decade of work as a radio host in St. Cloud, MN.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mrs. BACHMANN">Originally from Fargo, ND, Ox began his radio career in 1991 as a 
rock DJ out of Fergus Falls. He's come a long way since then, now 
hosting an afternoon show on weekdays in St. Cloud with popularity in 
the Twin Cities and here in D.C.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mrs. BACHMANN">He's not only an on-air personality and radio entrepreneur. Ox and 
his wife, Jan, have made an effort to stay involved and connected in 
the community. His involvement with Jaycees, Sertoma, Chamber of 
Commerce and the Boy Scouts haven't gone unnoticed. The St. Cloud Times 
named him one of the top 40 most influential people of the decade </speaking>
(2000-2010).
  <speaking name="Mrs. BACHMANN">As I continue on in my final year in the House of Representatives, I 
look back with appreciation and respect for the people of the 6th 
District. One of those special people is Dan Ochsner. With a 
personality as fiery as his hair, he can always be counted on to 
provide a humorous take on current events to the people of central 
Minnesota.</speaking>
  <speaking name="Mrs. BACHMANN">There are few people kinder, funnier, and more genuine than Ox. It's 
an honor to represent a district in the halls of Congress with talented 
individuals like Dan. The 6th District of Minnesota is lucky to call 
Dan Ochsner one of their own.</speaking>
</CRDoc>