<CRDoc>[Congressional Record Volume <volume>160</volume>, Number <number>37</number> (<weekday>Wednesday</weekday>, <month>March</month> <day>5</day>, <year>2014</year>)]
[<chamber>Extensions</chamber> of Remarks]
[Page <pages>E306</pages>]
<congress>113</congress>
<session>2</session>
          <document_title>RECOGNIZING THE NORTHERN VIRGINIA CONSERVATION TRUST</document_title>
                        <title>HON. GERALD E. CONNOLLY</title>
                              <title>of virginia</title>
                    <title>in the house of representatives</title>
                        <title>Wednesday, March 5, 2014</title>
  <speaker name="Mr. CONNOLLY">Mr. CONNOLLY</speaker>. <speaking name="Mr. CONNOLLY">Mr. Speaker, I rise to congratulate the Northern 
Virginia Conservation Trust for receiving accreditation by the National 
Land Trust Accreditation Commission. The accreditation process is very 
rigorous and signifies the highest standards of excellence in land 
conservation.
   When Congress first passed the tax incentives for land conservation, 
it placed a high degree of trust in non-profit land trusts to manage 
these transactions properly. Over the years, land conservation has 
become increasingly complex and requires careful adherence to the 
national Land Trust Standards and Practices. This accreditation process 
helps give taxpayers confidence that land trusts are a worthy public 
investment.
   I want to thank the Northern Virginia Conservation Trust for its 
dedication and effectiveness in educating the public about the 
importance of conservation and preserving local natural areas, trails, 
streams, and parks. Its work helps to protect wildlife habitat, water 
quality and healthy communities. Since its founding 20 years ago, the 
Trust has protected 5,370 acres across Northern Virginia. And, by 
achieving national accreditation, the Northern Virginia Conservation 
Trust has expanded its capacity to accomplish this mission far into the 
future.
   Mr. Speaker, I invite my colleagues to join me in commending the 
Northern Virginia Conservation Trust for its hard work and commitment 
to our community. I wish the Trust and its supporters continued success 
in their conservation efforts.</speaking>
</CRDoc>